4.What is SOAP? Why we use it? What is the difference between HTML5 and HTML?

SOAP is an acronym for Simple Object Access Protocol. 
It is an XML-based messaging protocol for exchanging information among different machines, operating systems or networks.
it is communicated over HTTP
SOAP is platform and language-independent.

Uses of soap:
SOAP mostly used for accessing web services.
it enables client applications to easily connect to remote services and invoke remote methods.
it can exchange complete documents or call a remote procedure transported via HTTP.

message structure:
A SOAP message is an ordinary XML document containing the following elements −

Envelope − Defines the start and the end of the message. It is a mandatory element.

Header − Contains any optional attributes of the message used in processing the message, 
either at an intermediary point or at the ultimate end-point. It is an optional element.

Body − Contains the XML data comprising the message being sent. It is a mandatory element.

Fault − An optional Fault element that provides information about errors that occur while processing the message.

Differences between HTML and HTML5:

1.Audio and video were not part of previous HTML version specifications, 
however, both are the integral part of HTML5 specifications.

2.SVG, canvas and other virtual vector graphics are integral part of HTML5,
while vector graphics is possible in HTML with the help of various technologies such as VML, Silver-light, Flash, etc.

3.HTML5 uses web SQL databases,web storage and application cache for temporary storing data, meanwhile, 
in HTML, only browser cache could be utilized for this purpose.

4.HTML doesn’t allows JavaScript to run in web browser, it runs in same thread as browser interface. 
HTML5 allows JavaScript to run in background that is possible because of JS Web worker API in HTML5.

5.HTML5 supports new kinds of form controls, 
for example: dates and times, email, number, range, tel, url, search etc.
Previously in html there were only a few types like text,password etc 

6.HTML works smoothly with all old browsers while 
most of the modern web browsers have started supporting HTML5 specifications. 

7.There are many new elements introduced in HTML. Some of the most important ones are: 
header,nav,article,section,aside summary,footer, 
audio,video,track,source, progress,
command,time, data, datalist, details, embed, wbr, figcaption, figure

